Victoria Vela

Software Engineer

(214) 334-7890 · victoriavela01@gmail.com · Rogers, AR · LinkedIn · Github · Portfolio

I am a software engineer who is energized by collaborating with team members to solve complex problems. Prior to becoming a software engineer, I spent 9 years in consumer goods sales where I successfully managed multi-million dollar accounts for retailers such as Walmart, Costco, and Whole Foods. As a web developer, I have a passion for improving user experience and am energized by delivering technology-based solutions.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, | Databases - Relational (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB)

Libraries and Frameworks - React JS, Express.js, Bootstrap, Materialize

Other - RESTful Routing, MVC architecture, object-oriented-programming, version control

Soft Skills - Collaboration, Time-Management, Leadership, Detail-Oriented, Strategic, Negotiation

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Gift Planner | An application for housing gift ideas

October 2022

- Single-handedly built a full stack Python/Django application with full CRUD and User Auth functionality.
- Used a relational database; PostgreSQL to implement a one to many relationship allowing users to add gift ideas to their respective boards
- Utilized Materialize framework and Flexbox to create a polished front end user interface.

Books2Read | App to browse and find your next book to read

September 2022

- Developed a React JS application with functional components utilizing the New York Times Books API
- Leveraged **React Router** and Integrated third party **API** calls into application to send GET requests
- Created a responsive, mobile friendly layout utilizing custom CSS (Flexbox, media queries)

LandPost | App for travel bloggers

August 2022

- Developed a Full-Stack Express app for travel bloggers using the MEN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express.js, Node.js) stack to handle full CRUD operations
- Collaborated with two other software engineers to plan and build out application utilizing version control and regular check-ins to ensure we hit our deadline
- Implemented User Authentication and Authorization in backend as well as Flexbox on front end to enhance the user interface

War Card Game | A browser based card game

July 2022

- Utilized HTML, CSS, & JavaScript to develop a web-based card game
- Implemented JavaScript for game logic such as card shuffle, war, and win/loss functionality. Implemented DOM manipulation to render the game in user-friendly format
- Applied a dynamic layout using **Flexbox** to control the user interface of the application

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Mills Inc. | Minneapolis, MN

August 2013 - June 2022

Customer Account Manager - Blue Buffalo Division (Albertsons)

January 2022 - June 2022

- Partnered with Albertsons corporate buying team through regular touchpoints and strategy sessions to achieve strategic objectives
- Grew distribution and dollar share by working with cross-functional teams to create and execute winning plans
- Maintained up to date forecasts which resulted in achieving our budgetary and sales volume goals
- Utilized syndicated data to influence merchandising and distribution decisions at Albertsons resulting in year over year sales growth

Customer Account Manager (Whole Foods & Nat/Org East)

October 2018 - January 2022

- Collaborated with marketing and finance to develop seasonal display plans resulting in year over year dollar sales growth
- Analyzed and executed a more efficient merchandising plan worth 3% budgetary savings over the year prior

Negotiated the addition of three new items to the assortment which led to year over year distribution and dollar growth

Trade Planning Lead (HEB, Meijer, Publix)

February 2018 - October 2018

- Managed the centralized planning team on the Cereal business unit
- Supported customer teams by providing trade, volume, and forecasting strategies and solutions
- Utilized syndicated data to create sales decks for customer teams to leverage resulting in distribution gains on shelf

Trade Planning Lead (Walmart)

August 2013 - February 2018

- Profitably managed General Mills' multi-million dollar trade budget for Walmart Snacks business
- Accurately forecasted sales volume outlook to deliver on key strategic business and financial targets

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

July 2022 - October 2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

University of Arkansas, Sam M Walton School of Business | Fayetteville, AR

Graduated May 2013

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration (Marketing)

GPA: 3.77